

### CONTACT

•

Uberlândia, MG

**B** 

Rua Afonso Arinos, 700 Apto. 1301, Bairro Tubalina Uberlândia, MG



(34) 99644-8447



lucas.ep@outlook.com



github.com/lucasaor



# SKILLS

Machine Learning

Agiles

C/C++

C#

Power BI

Python

Microsoft Off

Pandas/Scikit-Learn

SQL

# LANGUAGES

Portuguese \_\_\_\_\_

English

Spariisti

Resume built in VueJS.

## LUCAS ANTÔNIO OLIVEIRA

### RODRIGUES

PH.D. ENGINEER | DATA SCIENTIST

Ph.D. Mechatronic Engineer, Data Scientist and Technology enthusiast, with both professional and academic experience. Business Analyst for 3 year and researcher for the last 5 years. Acquainted with agile methodologies, self-taught, and proficient in several programming languages and technologies. Experiences as freelancer in IoT projects and as programming instructor.

# EXPERIENCE

Reasearcher - Federal University of Uberlândia 2015 - 2020

Ph.D researcher of the Robotics and Automation Laboratory, working with the following main topics:

Development of rehabilitation robotic structures for human gait recovery in post-stroke patients;

Optimizatin of robotic and mechanical systems appling machine learning techniques;

Data integration systems between robotic structures and virtual serious games applied in rehabilitation protocols.

Educational robotics and programming instructor - HappyCode 2017 - 2017

Teacher and instructor for kids and teenagers of the following topics:

Game development applying Unity 2D/3D, C# and Java;

Drones and educational robots;

2012 - 2015

Business Analyst - Algar Tech

infrastructure. Responsible for price formation, requirements documentations and business case development for government and private companies.

Development of corporative solutions on Telecominucations services and

Local network, IP phones and workstation infrastructure projects; Firewalls e Data Storage solutions;

Professional Services:

Install and maintenance projects of optical fiber transmission systems;

Cisco Equipments solutions.

Junior Company 2008 - 2010

internal with the academic community, events and workshop

Marketing team member, Marketing Director - META Consultoria -

organizations. Leader of a team with 4 co-workers and member of the Directive Council of the junior company.

Responsible for the external communication of the company and for the

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Mechatronics Engineering - Federal University of Uberlândia 2017 - 2020, Development of a novel active bodyweight support for

human gait rehabilitation applying machine learning and computational methods for optimization.

Uberlândia
2015 - 2017, Development of nonmotorized structures for human lower

Master in Mechatronics Engineering - Federal University of

limb rehabilitation applying machine learning and computational methods for optimization.

Uberlândia
2008 - 2014, A mixed graduation course combining skills from

Graduation in Mechatronics Engineering - Federal University of

Mechanical Engineering, Electric Engineering and Computer Science.

**PROJECTS** 

2020, Independent studies, courses projects and online challenges on

Data Analysis on Open Data Sets

Data Science common topics.

Freelancer Consultant in microcontrollers and IoT Solutions

2017, Projects developed for a small IT Agribusiness Company in the following topics:

Realtime biometric registering for employees using microcontrollers;

Development of a smart scale for ration stock control;

Development of a communication protocol over mobile internet shield between microcontrollers and the main database.

